So in college,
عندما كنت في الجامعة ..
I was a government major,
كان تخصصي في العمل الحكومي
which means I had to write a lot of papers.
ما يعني أن علي كتابة الكثير من الأوراق،
Now, when a normal student writes a paper,
الآن عندما يكتب أي طالب عادي ورقة
they might spread the work out a little like this.
يبدو جدول عمله هكذا تقريبا..
So, you know --
كما ترون..
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
you get started maybe a little slowly,
يكون العمل في البداية بطيئاً ،
but you get enough done in the first week
لكنك تنجز خلال الأسبوع الأول بما يكفي
that, with some heavier days later on,
لأن يجعلك ترى الأيام الثقيلة القادمة
everything gets done, things stay civil.
تبدو منتجة و لطيفة ..
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I would want to do that like that.
و أنا أتمنى أن أفعل هذا بالشكل نفسه،
That would be the plan.
هكذا ستكون الخطة..
I would have it all ready to go,
سأبدأ بكتابة الجدول للشروع في العمل،
but then, actually, the paper would come along,
ثم يأتي الوقت للكتابة ..
and then I would kind of do this.
و ينتهي بي الأمر هكذا !
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And that would happen every single paper.
و هذا يحدث في كل ورقة أكتبها ..
But then came my 90-page senior thesis,
إلى أن طلب مني كتابة أطروحة التخرج من 90 صفحة ،
a paper you're supposed to spend a year on.
ورقة من المفترض أن نعمل عليها طوال العام !
And I knew for a paper like that, my normal work flow was not an option.
و لورقة كهذه ، جدول عملي المعتاد لم يكن خيارًا ..
It was way too big a project.
لأن المشروع كان ضخماً جداً
So I planned things out,
بدأت التخطيط للمشروع ،
and I decided I kind of had to go something like this.
و قررت أن الجدول يجب أن يشبه شيئاً كهذا ..
This is how the year would go.
هكذا ستمضي السنة ..
So I'd start off light,
سأبدأ بالعمل السهل و الخفيف ،
and I'd bump it up in the middle months,
ثم سأزيد الجهد قليلا في منتصف السنة ،
and then at the end, I would kick it up into high gear
و في نهاية العام سأعمل بأقصى جهد لدي ..
just like a little staircase.
سيكون سهلًا جداً كصعود السلم ، درجة درجة .
How hard could it be to walk up the stairs?
كم يمكن أن يكون صعود الدرج صعبًا ؟
No big deal, right?
ليس بالأمر الكبير ، صحيح ؟
But then, the funniest thing happened.
لكن حصل لي أطرف شيء ..
Those first few months?
في الشهور الأولى ،
They came and went,
جاءت و مضت بسرعة،
and I couldn't quite do stuff.
و لم أستطع تأدية أي شيء .
So we had an awesome new revised plan.
فقررت أن أغير خطتي قليلا ..
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And then --
ثم ...
But then those middle months actually went by,
لكن في الحقيقة مضى منتصف العام بسرعة،
and I didn't really write words,
و لم أكتب كلمة واحدة .
and so we were here.
فأصبحت الآن هنا !
And then two months turned into one month,
تقلص الشهرين لشهر واحد ..
which turned into two weeks.
ثم إلى أسبوعين ..
And one day I woke up
و في أحد الأيام استيقظت ،
with three days until the deadline,
و لم يبق إلا ثلاثة أيام على التسليم !!
still not having written a word,
و لم أكتب أي كلمة حتى الآن ،
and so I did the only thing I could:
ففعلت الشيء الوحيد الذي يمكنني فعله ،
I wrote 90 pages over 72 hours,
كتبت 90 صفحة في 72 ساعة ،
pulling not one but two all-nighters --
وواصلت يومين كاملين بدون نوم ..
humans are not supposed to pull two all-nighters --
و لا يجب على البشر السهر يومين بدون نوم ،
sprinted across campus,
هرعت جريًا إلى الجامعة ،
dove in slow motion,
بالحركة البطيئة سلمت الورقة على
and got it in just at the deadline.
الموعد المحدد بالضبط !
I thought that was the end of everything.
ظننت أنني أنجزت كل شيء .
But a week later I get a call,
بعد أسبوع ، جائني اتصال ،
and it's the school.
كان اتصالًا من الجامعة .
And they say, "Is this Tim Urban?"
سألوا: "هل أنت تيم أوربن؟"
And I say, "Yeah."
فجاوبت: "نعم."
And they say, "We need to talk about your thesis."
قالوا: "يجب أن نتناقش معك بخصوص أطروحتك" ..
And I say, "OK."
قلت : "حسنًا."
And they say,
فقالوا ..
"It's the best one we've ever seen."
"إنها أفضل أطروحة رأيناها في حياتنا" !
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
That did not happen.
هذا لم يحصل في الحقيقة ،
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It was a very, very bad thesis.
كانت أطروحة سيئة إلى أبعد الحدود ..
I just wanted to enjoy that one moment when all of you thought,
أردت فقط أن أستمتع باللحظة عندما ظننتم :
"This guy is amazing!"
"هذا الرجل مذهل"!
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
No, no, it was very, very bad.
لا، لا، كانت سيئة جدا
Anyway, today I'm a writer-blogger guy.
على كل حال ، اليوم أنا كاتب و مدون في الإنترنت ..
I write the blog Wait But Why.
أكتب في مدونة اسمها "انتظر لكن لماذا؟"
And a couple of years ago, I decided to write about procrastination.
قبل سنتين قررت أن أدون عن التسويف والتأجيل
My behavior has always perplexed the non-procrastinators around me,
كانت تصرفاتي دائمًا تحيِّر غير المسوِّفين من حولي ولماذا أؤجل أعمالي
and I wanted to explain to the non-procrastinators of the world
فأردت أن أشرح لهؤلاء و للعالم ، ما يجري في
what goes on in the heads of procrastinators,
رؤوس الذين يسوفون و يؤجلون أعمالهم ،
and why we are the way we are.
و لماذا نحن هكذا .
Now, I had a hypothesis
كانت لدي نظرية تقول
that the brains of procrastinators were actually different
أن عقول المسوِّفين حقيقةً
than the brains of other people.
تختلف عن الأشخاص الآخرين
And to test this, I found an MRI lab
و لاختبار هذا ، وجدت مختبرًا سمح لي
that actually let me scan both my brain
باستخدام جهاز الرنين المغناطيسي لتصوير مخي
and the brain of a proven non-procrastinator,
ومخ رجل آخر لايؤجل أعماله
so I could compare them.
لأستطيع المقارنة بينهما ،
I actually brought them here to show you today.
و أحضرت الصور معي لترونها اليوم بنفسكم ،
I want you to take a look carefully to see if you can notice a difference.
أريدكم الآن أن تأخذوا نظرة فاحصة لتلاحظوا إن كان هناك اختلاف ..
I know that if you're not a trained brain expert,
أنا أعلم أنه ليس كلكم خبراء ،
it's not that obvious, but just take a look, OK?
و أنها ليست واضحة و لكن فقط انظروا ، حسنًا ؟
So here's the brain of a non-procrastinator.
إذًا هنا صورة مخ الذي لا يؤجل ،
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now ...
و الآن ..
here's my brain.
هنا صورة مخي .
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
There is a difference.
هناك فرق .
Both brains have a Rational Decision-Maker in them,
كلا العقلين يحتويان على (متخذ القرار العقلاني)
but the procrastinator's brain
لكن عقل المسوِّف
also has an Instant Gratification Monkey.
يحتوي أيضًا على (قرد المتعة الفورية)
Now, what does this mean for the procrastinator?
الآن ، ماذا يعني هذا للمسوف ؟
Well, it means everything's fine until this happens.
يعني أن كل شيء بخير حتى يحدث هذا ..
[This is a perfect time to get some work done.] [Nope!]
الرجل: "هذا هو الوقت المثالي لإنجاز العمل" القرد : "لا!"
So the Rational Decision-Maker will make the rational decision
إذا سيقوم (متخذ القرار المنطقي) بالقيام
to do something productive,
بشيء مفيد و منتج .
but the Monkey doesn't like that plan,
لكن القرد لا تعجبه الخطة،
so he actually takes the wheel,
فيأخذ القرد العجلة و يقول :
and he says, "Actually, let's read the entire Wikipedia page
لماذا لا نقرأ صفحة ويكيبيديا كاملة
of the Nancy Kerrigan/ Tonya Harding scandal,
عن فضيحة نانسي و تونيا (ممثلات)لأنني
because I just remembered that that happened.
تذكرت للتو أن هذا حصل !
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Then --
ثم ..
Then we're going to go over to the fridge,
ثم سنذهب إلى الثلاجة
to see if there's anything new in there since 10 minutes ago.
لنرى إذا تغير أي شيء فيها منذ 10 دقائق ..
After that, we're going to go on a YouTube spiral
بعد ذلك ، سندخل دوامة اليوتيوب التي تبدأ
that starts with videos of Richard Feynman talking about magnets
بفيديوهات عن ريتشارد فاينمان (عالم) يتحدث عن المغناطيس
and ends much, much later with us watching interviews
و تنتهي بعد فترة طويلة جدًا بمشاهدة مقابلات
with Justin Bieber's mom.
مع أم جاستن بيبر (مغني) ..
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"All of that's going to take a while,
القرد: "كل هذا سيأخذ وقت ،
so we're not going to really have room on the schedule for any work today.
و لا توجد مساحة لعمل أي شيء اليوم .
Sorry!"
"آسف!"
(Sigh)
(ضحك)
Now, what is going on here?
الآن ، ما الذي يجري هنا !
The Instant Gratification Monkey does not seem like a guy
هذا القرد لا يبدو كشخص تريده
you want behind the wheel.
قائدًا خلف الدفة .
He lives entirely in the present moment.
هو يعيش كليًا في اللحظة الراهنة ،
He has no memory of the past, no knowledge of the future,
لا يوجد لديه ذاكرة للماضي و لا أدنى معرفة بالمستقبل ..
and he only cares about two things:
هو يهتم بشيئين فقط :
easy and fun.
"سهل و ممتع"
Now, in the animal world, that works fine.
في عالم الحيوان ، هذا يجري بشكل مثالي .
If you're a dog
إذا كنت كلبا ،
and you spend your whole life doing nothing other than easy and fun things,
ولم تفعل أي شي سوى السهل و الممتع ،
you're a huge success!
فأنت ناجح بكل المقاييس !
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And to the Monkey,
وللقرود ،
humans are just another animal species.
البشر هم فقط نوع آخر من الحيوانات .
You have to keep well-slept, well-fed and propagating into the next generation,
يأكلون ، ينامون و يتكاثرون ..
which in tribal times might have worked OK.
الأمر الذي سيكون طبيعيًّا في الأزمان البدائية .
But, if you haven't noticed, now we're not in tribal times.
لكن، إن لم تلاحظ، نحن لسنا في تلك الأزمان
We're in an advanced civilization, and the Monkey does not know what that is.
نحن في زمن متطور و حضاري و القرد لا يعرف معنى ذلك .
Which is why we have another guy in our brain,
و لهذا السبب يوجد في رأسنا
the Rational Decision-Maker,
(متخذ القرار المنطقي) ،
who gives us the ability to do things no other animal can do.
الذي يعطينا قدرات لا يستطيع أي حيوان آخر القيام بها ،
We can visualize the future.
نستطيع تخيل المستقبل ،
We can see the big picture.
نستطيع رؤية الصورة الكاملة
We can make long-term plans.
و نستطيع القيام بخطط طويلة المدى ..
And he wants to take all of that into account.
فيأخذ متخذ القرار كل هذا في الحسبان ،
And he wants to just have us do
ويريدنا أن نفعل فقط ما يبدو
whatever makes sense to be doing right now.
صحيحًا ومنطقياً فعله الآن ..
Now, sometimes it makes sense
وفي بعض الأحيان يبدو فعل شيء ما
to be doing things that are easy and fun,
منطقيًا و ممتعا في نفس الوقت ،
like when you're having dinner or going to bed
كحضور عشاء أو الذهاب للنوم ،
or enjoying well-earned leisure time.
أو الاستمتاع في أوقت الفراغ .
That's why there's an overlap.
لهذا يوجد تداخل بين المنطقي و الممتع ..
Sometimes they agree.
بعض الأحيان يتوافقوا ،
But other times, it makes much more sense
و في أوقات أخرى ، يبدو منطقيًا أكثر
to be doing things that are harder and less pleasant,
أن تعمل في شيء صعب و غير ممتع
for the sake of the big picture.
من أجل المنفعة الكبرى .
And that's when we have a conflict.
و هنا يحصل التعارض .
And for the procrastinator,
و بالنسبة للمسوِّف ،
that conflict tends to end a certain way every time,
هذا التعارض ينتهي دائمًا بالطريقة نفسها ،
leaving him spending a lot of time in this orange zone,
مما يجعله يقضي معظم وقته في المنطقة البرتقالية ،
an easy and fun place that's entirely out of the Makes Sense circle.
منطقة ممتعة و سهلة و منفصلة كليا عن دائرة المنطق .
I call it the Dark Playground.
أسميها (حديقة الألعاب المظلمة) .
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now, the Dark Playground is a place
الآن ، (حديقة الألعاب المظلمة) مكان
that all of you procrastinators out there know very well.
تعرفونه كلكم أيها المسوِّفون جيدًا .
It's where leisure activities happen
مكان تحدث فيه نشاطات أوقات الفراغ
at times when leisure activities are not supposed to be happening.
في وقت ليس وقت فراغ فعليًا .
The fun you have in the Dark Playground
المرح الذي تحظى به في (حديقة الألعاب المظلمة)
isn't actually fun, because it's completely unearned,
ليس مرحًا حقيقياً ، لأنه غير مستحق نهائيًا
and the air is filled with guilt, dread, anxiety, self-hatred --
و الجو من حولك يمتلئ بالذنب، التعاسة، القلق وكره النفس
all of those good procrastinator feelings.
كل مشاعر المسوِّفين الجميلة ..
And the question is, in this situation, with the Monkey behind the wheel,
و السؤال عندما يكون القرد خلف العجلة هو :
how does the procrastinator ever get himself over here to this blue zone,
كيف ينقل المسوِّف نفسه إلى المنطقة الزرقاء ،
a less pleasant place, but where really important things happen?
منطقة تحدث فيها أشياء أقل مرح و سهولة لكنها أهم بكثير ..
Well, turns out the procrastinator has a guardian angel,
حسنًا ، تبين أن الذي يؤجل أعماله لديه مَلَكْ حارس ،
someone who's always looking down on him and watching over him
شخص يراقبه دائمًا و ينظر إليه
in his darkest moments --
في أظلم و أحلك لحظاته ..
someone called the Panic Monster.
شخص يسمى (وحش الفزع)
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now, the Panic Monster is dormant most of the time,
الآن (وحش الفزع) نائم معظم الأوقات ..
but he suddenly wakes up anytime a deadline gets too close
لكنه يستيقظ فجأة ، عندما يقترب أي موعد نهائي جدًّا
or there's danger of public embarrassment,
أو أن يكون هناك خطر من الإحراج أمام الناس
a career disaster or some other scary consequence.
أو خسارة الوظيفة ، أو أي عاقبة مخيفة ..
And importantly, he's the only thing the Monkey is terrified of.
و أهم شيء أنه الشيء الوحيد الذي يخيف القرد .
Now, he became very relevant in my life pretty recently,
الآن ، هذا الوحش أصبح متصلًا بحياتي في الفترة الأخيرة ،
because the people of TED reached out to me about six months ago
لأن مسؤولي مؤتمر TED تواصلوا معي قبل ستة أشهر
and invited me to do a TED Talk.
و دعوني للتكلم فيه .
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now, of course, I said yes.
بالطبع قلت : نعم، كان حلمي دائمًا أن
It's always been a dream of mine to have done a TED Talk in the past.
أتكلم في مؤتمر TED في الماضي
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
But in the middle of all this excitement,
و في وسط كل هذه الحماسة ،
the Rational Decision-Maker seemed to have something else on his mind.
كان متخذ القرار يفكر بشيء آخر .
He was saying, "Are we clear on what we just accepted?
كان يقول: "هل نحن واضحون بشأن ما وافقنا عليه قبل قليل ؟
Do we get what's going to be now happening one day in the future?
هل نحن نعلم ما سيحصل في يوم ما في المستقبل ؟
We need to sit down and work on this right now."
يجب أن نجلس و نجهز الخطاب حالًا"
And the Monkey said, "Totally agree, but let's just open Google Earth
قال القرد: أتفق معك بالكامل لكن ما رأيك أن نفتح خرائط قوقل ،
and zoom in to the bottom of India, like 200 feet above the ground,
و نقرب الصورة على قاع الهند و نستكشفها
and scroll up for two and a half hours til we get to the top of the country,
لمدة ساعتان ونصف إلى أن نصل لأعلى الهند ،
so we can get a better feel for India."
لكي نثقف نفسنا عن هذه البلد" .
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So that's what we did that day.
فهذا ما فعلناه ذاك اليوم .
As six months turned into four and then two and then one,
تحولت 6 شهور إلى 4 ثم إلى 2 ثم إلى شهر واحد..
the people of TED decided to release the speakers.
قرر مؤتمر TED إعلان المتحدثين في المؤتمر ،
And I opened up the website, and there was my face
و عندما فتحت الموقع ، وجدت صورة وجهي
staring right back at me.
تحدق في وجهي .
And guess who woke up?
و خمنوا من استيقظ ؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So the Panic Monster starts losing his mind,
بدأ (وحش الفزع) يفقد عقله ..
and a few seconds later, the whole system's in mayhem.
و في ثوان قليلة ، تحول النظام إلى فوضى .
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And the Monkey -- remember, he's terrified of the Panic Monster --
و قام القرد - تذكروا، القرد يخاف من وحش الفزع -
boom, he's up the tree!
و صعد جريا إلى الشجرة!
And finally,
و أخيرًا،
finally, the Rational Decision-Maker can take the wheel
استطاع (متخذ القرار المنطقي) استلام الدفة
and I can start working on the talk.
و استطعت بدء العمل على المحاضرة
Now, the Panic Monster explains
الآن (وحش الفزع) يمثل
all kinds of pretty insane procrastinator behavior,
كل أنواع التصرفات المجنونة عند المسوِّفين ،
like how someone like me could spend two weeks
مثل كيف استطعت أنا أن أمضي أسبوعين
unable to start the opening sentence of a paper,
كل أنواع التصرفات على كتابة جملة واحدة في أطروحتي ،
and then miraculously find the unbelievable work ethic
ثم بإعجاز ، تأتي الكلمات بشكل متواصل في
to stay up all night and write eight pages.
يومين لأكتب 8 صفحات !.
And this entire situation, with the three characters --
هذه الحالة بكاملها مع الثلاث شخصيات ،
this is the procrastinator's system.
هذا هو نظام المسوِّف .
It's not pretty, but in the end, it works.
ليس جميلا ، لكنه في النهاية ، يعمل .
This is what I decided to write about on the blog a couple of years ago.
و هذا ما قررت كتابته على المدونة قبل سنتين
When I did, I was amazed by the response.
و عندما كتبت، ذُهلت بالردود ،
Literally thousands of emails came in,
آلاف الرسائل وصلتني ،
from all different kinds of people from all over the world,
من كل أنواع الناس ، من شتى أنحاء العالم ،
doing all different kinds of things.
يعملون كل أنواع الوظائف .
These are people who were nurses, bankers, painters, engineers
كان منهم ممرضين، مصرفيين، رسامين، مهندسين
and lots and lots of PhD students.
و الكثير الكثير من طلاب الدكتوراه ،
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And they were all writing, saying the same thing:
و كلهم قالوا يكتبون قائلين نفس الشيء :
"I have this problem too."
"لدي نفس المشكلة" .
But what struck me was the contrast between the light tone of the post
الذي أدهشني كان التناقض بين خفة الكلام
and the heaviness of these emails.
الذي كتبته و ثقل هذه الرسائل ،
These people were writing with intense frustration
هؤلاء الناس كانوا يكتبون بإحباط شديد
about what procrastination had done to their lives,
عن ماذا فعل لهم التسويف في حياتهم ،
about what this Monkey had done to them.
عن ماذا فعل هذا القرد لهم .
And I thought about this, and I said,
و عندما فكرت بالأمر قلت لنفسي :
well, if the procrastinator's system works, then what's going on?
لو كان نظام التسويف يعمل ، فماذا الذي يحصل ؟
Why are all of these people in such a dark place?
لم هؤلاء الأشخاص محبطين بشدة ؟
Well, it turns out that there's two kinds of procrastination.
تبين أنه هنالك نوعان من التسويف ،
Everything I've talked about today, the examples I've given,
كل شيء تحدثت عنه اليوم ، جميع الأمثلة ،
they all have deadlines.
كلها لها موعد نهائي .
And when there's deadlines,
و عندما يكون هناك مواعيد نهائية ،
the effects of procrastination are contained to the short term
، تأثير التأجيل يُحتوى و يُضغط على المدى القصير
because the Panic Monster gets involved.
لأن (وحش الفزع) يتدخل ..
But there's a second kind of procrastination
لكن هناك نوع آخر من التأجيل ،
that happens in situations when there is no deadline.
نوع يحدث في ظروف ليس لها موعد نهائي .
So if you wanted a career where you're a self-starter --
مثلًا، إذا كنت تريد أن تبدأ عملًا حرًّا ،
something in the arts, something entrepreneurial --
شيئًا في الفن ، أو عملًا رياديًّا ..
there's no deadlines on those things at first, because nothing's happening,
هذه الأعمال ليس لها مواعيد نهائية في البداية ، لأن لا شيء حدث من الأصل .
not until you've gone out and done the hard work
بينما لو خرجت و بدأت بالعمل الصعب
to get momentum, get things going.
لتكتسب بعض النشاط للقيام بالأعمال الأخرى .
There's also all kinds of important things outside of your career
هناك أيضًا الكثير من الأعمال المهمة خارج نطاق عملك
that don't involve any deadlines,
و لا تتضمن مواعيد نهائية ..
like seeing your family or exercising and taking care of your health,
مثل زيارة أهلك أو الرياضة و الاهتمام بصحتك ،
working on your relationship
العمل لتطوير علاقاتك ،
or getting out of a relationship that isn't working.
أو قطع علاقات سيئة ..
Now if the procrastinator's only mechanism of doing these hard things
الآن ، لو كانت طريقة المسوِّف الوحيدة لإنهاء هذه الأشياء الصعبة
is the Panic Monster, that's a problem,
هي عن طريق (وحش الفزع) ، هناك مشكلة ،
because in all of these non-deadline situations,
لأن في كل هذه الأعمال المهمة التي لا تحتوي على مواعيد نهائية
the Panic Monster doesn't show up.
الوحش لن يظهر .
He has nothing to wake up for,
لا يوجد له موعد يستيقظ من أجله .
so the effects of procrastination, they're not contained;
إذاً ، تأثير التأجيل لن يُحتوى
they just extend outward forever.
و بالتالي ، هذه الأعمال ستستمر و تمتد للأبد ..
And it's this long-term kind of procrastination
و هذا هو نوع التسويف طويل المدى
that's much less visible and much less talked about
الذي لايُرى ولا يٌتَكَلم كثيرًا عنه
than the funnier, short-term deadline-based kind.
مثل النوع الأول : المرح ، قصير المدى و المحتوي على مواعيد نهائية.
It's usually suffered quietly and privately.
و بالعادة يعاني الناس من النوع الثاني بهدوء و خصوصية ..
And it can be the source
و هذا التسويف قد يكون مصدرًا
of a huge amount of long-term unhappiness, and regrets.
كبيرًا لحزن و ندم طويل المدى .
And I thought, that's why those people are emailing,
ففكرت : لهذا هؤلاء الناس يراسلونني ،
and that's why they're in such a bad place.
و لهذا هم في حالة سيئة كهذه .
It's not that they're cramming for some project.
ليس لأنهم يهدفون لمشروع معين ،
It's that long-term procrastination has made them feel like a spectator,
بل بسبب ذاك التأجيل طويل المدى الذي جعلهم كالمتفرجين ،
at times, in their own lives.
أحيانًا ، على حياتهم نفسها ..
The frustration is not that they couldn't achieve their dreams;
إحباطهم لا يأتي من عدم تحقيق أحلامهم ،
it's that they weren't even able to start chasing them.
بل لأنهم لم يستطيعوا السعي لها من الأساس .
So I read these emails and I had a little bit of an epiphany --
فبينما قرأت الرسائل أتاني نوع من الإلهام :
that I don't think non-procrastinators exist.
أني لا أظن أن هنالك أحدًا لا يُؤجل أعماله ،
That's right -- I think all of you are procrastinators.
هذا صحيح ، أعتقد أنكم كلكم مسوِّفون ،
Now, you might not all be a mess,
بالطبع ، قد لا تكونوا فوضويين ..
like some of us,
مثل بعضنا .
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
and some of you may have a healthy relationship with deadlines,
و بعضكم قد يكون على علاقة جيدة مع المواعيد و الالتزام بها .
but remember: the Monkey's sneakiest trick
لكن تذكروا : خدعة القرد السرية هي
is when the deadlines aren't there.
عندما لا يكون هناك موعد نهائي .
Now, I want to show you one last thing.
الآن ، أريد أن أريكم شيئًا أخيرًا ..
I call this a Life Calendar.
أسمي هذا : (جدول الحياة)
That's one box for every week of a 90-year life.
كل مربع يمثل أسبوعًا في حياة 90 سنة ،
That's not that many boxes,
لا يبدو أن هناك الكثير منها ..
especially since we've already used a bunch of those.
خصوصًا أننا استخدمنا الكثير منها في السابق
So I think we need to all take a long, hard look at that calendar.
أظن أننا جميعًا نحتاج أن نأخذ نظرة عميقة على هذا الجدول .
We need to think about what we're really procrastinating on,
و يجب علينا التفكير عن ما نؤجله حقيقةً ،
because everyone is procrastinating on something in life.
لأن كل واحدٍ منَّا لديه شيء يؤجله في حياته
We need to stay aware of the Instant Gratification Monkey.
يجب أن نبقى حذرين من قرد المتعة الفورية ،
That's a job for all of us.
هذه وظيفة لنا كلنا .
And because there's not that many boxes on there,
و لأنه لا يوجد ذاك العدد الكثير من الصناديق في الجدول ،
it's a job that should probably start today.
فهذه وظيفة يجب عليك أن تبدأها من اليوم .
Well, maybe not today, but ...
امممم ، ربما ليس " اليوم " لكن ..
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
You know.
كما تعلمون ،
Sometime soon.
في وقت ما قريب ...
Thank you.
شكرًا .